Guide to the Y. Ping Sun awards and related papers, 1995-2022 MS 1031
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Y. Ping Sun awards and related papers
1995-2022
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Sun, Y. Ping
MS 1031
6 Linear Feet 4 cartons and 2 oversized boxes
This collection includes memorabilia, photographs, crystal awards, correspondence, newsclippings, and other publications.
Biographical / Historical
Y. Ping Sun was born in Shanghai, China in 1957. She was raised by her grandparents in Tianjin, China because her parents worked in the military and frequently moved around the country. For secondary school, Ping was selected to attend a special school for foreign languages, where she studied English. She went on to become a member of the first group of Chinese students after the Cultural Revolution to take the college entrance exam in 1977 and be accepted into a Chinese university. Before she graduated from the Beijing Languages Institute, however, Ping was accepted into Princeton University, where she attended the Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs from 1981 to 1985. After an internship at a law firm during her junior year of college, she decided to become a lawyer and attended Columbia Law School from 1985 to 1988. Ping's first job after law school was at an international corporate law firm in New York called White & Case, LLP. After four years there, she moved to France for a year during her husband's sabbatical leave. When she returned to New York, Ping worked at Sidley Austin Brown & Wood, LLP, another international corporate firm. After working there for eleven years, she moved to Houston when her husband became the President of Rice University. Ping now serves as a University Representative for Rice and is a counsel at Yetter Coleman, LLP. She is on the board of several nonprofit organizations where she represents Rice to the greater Houston community.
Content Description
This collection includes memorabilia, photographs, crystal awards, correspondence, newsclippings, and other publications.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research. Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The materials were donated by Y. Ping Sun in June 2022.
Index Terms
Subjects
Asian Americans
Places
Rice University; Texas--Houston
- Series I: Documents, Certificates, Books and Magazines, Papers
  - Speeches, 2013-2019 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2005-2022 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Newspaper Articles, 2005-2021 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Magazines, 1995-2011 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Magazines, 2012-2022 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Certificates, 2004-2017 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Story About Ping, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Tianjin Foreign Languages School, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Asia Society Texas Center, 2014 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Southern News Media Group 30th Anniversary, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Handbook for Honorable Guests, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series II: Memorabilia
  - Lanyards, 2015-2021 (Box 1, Envelope 12)
  - Friends of Fondren Gala Fans (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series III: Plaques and Awards
  - Ping-Pong Diplomacy Plaque (Box 1, Envelope 14)
  - CKW Luxe Magazine, 2017 (Box 1, Envelope 15)
  - Mayor International Trade and Development Council Plaque, 2015 (Box 1, Envelope 16)
  - Friendship Ambassador Award by US-China People's Friendship Association, 2014 (Box 2, Case 1)
  - United Way Board of Trustees, 2016-2022 (Box 2, Case 2)
  - Teach for America (Box 2, Case 3)
  - BARC Distinguished Service, 2015-2018 (Box 2, Case 4)
  - Kaleidoscope of Learning Gala, 2012 (Box 2, Frame 5)
  - Gulf Coast Women in Leadership Symposium, 2016 (Box 2, Case 6)
  - Appreciating Award, 2006 (Box 3, Item 1)
  - Global Leader of Influence, 2021 (Box 3, Item 2)
  - Celebrating the Tudor Fieldhouse and paying tribute to The Curtain, Autry Court, 2008 (Box 3, Item 3)
  - Diversity Summit ACAP, 2016 (Box 3, Item 4)
  - Success to Significance Honoree, 2015 (Box 3, Item 5)
  - Most Powerful & Influential Women of Texas, 2015 (Box 3, Item 6)
  - Asian American Leadership Award, 2011 (Box 3, Item 7)
  - Mothers' Day Soirée Honoree, 2017 (Box 4, Item 1)
  - Spirit Award Rice University, 2013-2014 (Box 4, Item 2)
  - IACCGH "Women Mean Busine$$", 2015 (Box 4, Item 3)
  - Special Merit Award (Box 4, Item 4)
  - Founding Member of the Advisory Board of the Kinder Institute for Urban Research, 2017 (Box 4, Item 5)
  - United Way of Greater Houston Board of Trustee, 2007-2015 (Box 4, Item 6)
  - The Houston Lawyer, 2011 (Box 5, Frame 1)
  - Lunar New Year: Year of the Boar stamp (signed on back), 2019 (Box 5, Frame 2)
  - Rice Owls 5K Fun Run & Walk (Box 5, Frame 3)
- Series IV: Oversize Items
  - Painting, 2013 (Box 6, Item 1)
  - Proclamations, 2015-2021 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Recognitions, 1995-2014 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Chinese Newspapers, 2007-2013 (Box 6, Folder 5)